■
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译制作
更多美剧更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
坦纳
Tanner.
埃莫森正在局里和他的人商量
Emerson spoke to his man inside the bureau.
-他说你是清白的  -很好
He says you're clear. good.
我需要布置我的人准备下一项任务
Look, I need to prep my men on the next job,
你说接下来怎么做吧
So why don't you tell me what we need.
我到达后会把细节告诉你
I'll give you the specs when I get there.
我来抓他  你掩护我的侧翼
I'll engage him. cover my flank.
放心吧
I can handle it.
我搞不懂
I don't understand.
阿尔梅达正在精心策划这些袭击
Almeida was orchestrating these attacks.
如果他没有CIP装置  谁有
If he doesn't have the cip device, who does?
阿尔梅达为朱马政权工作
Almeida's working for the Juma regime.
我是杜巴库上校
This is colonel ike dubaku.
我们要求美国海军
We demand an immediate withdrawal
到明天的这个时候
Of the u.s. naval strike force
必须全部撤出
By this time tomorrow...
美军仍然驻扎在我们国家的周边地区
The American troops are still in position near our country.
泰勒总统刚刚收到了你们的请求
President taylor just received your demands.
看来是时候让我们
The perhaps it is time
给你们点颜色看看了
For a more forceful demonstration.
我了解萨曼莎·罗斯
I know about samantha roth.
她隐瞒了一些关于我儿子被谋杀的信息
She's hiding something about my son's murder.
罗杰是自杀的
Roger wasn't murdered.
我对你隐瞒了一些事情
I wasn't completely honest with you.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
罗杰没有自杀 泰勒先生
Roger didn't commit suicide, mr. taylor.
他是被谋杀的
He was murdered.
杰克  托尼不是恐怖分子
Jack, tony is not a terrorist.
他为我工作
He's working with me.
我们的工作  政府并不知情
We're working outside the government.
那就是为什么
That's why we have
我要托尼继续做卧底的原因
To get tony back undercover.
鲍尔  你不可能从这里逃出去的
Bauer, you're not going to make it out of here.
闭嘴  我让你闭嘴
Shut up. I said shut up!
卧倒
Get down!
我要带你离开这回去继续做卧底
We got to get you out of here and back undercover.
快走
Go!
托尼  我们走
Tony, let's go!
蕾妮  警卫看到鲍尔和阿尔梅达
Renee... security saw Bauer and Almeida
乘一辆深蓝色货车逃走了
Getting into a dark-colored panel van.
-他们向哪个方向跑了  -西面
What direction were they heading? west.
交通摄像机怎么了
What's happening with tdot. cameras?
我在努力调取  但是无法读取图像
I've been trying. traffic images aren't loading.
无法读取是什么意思
What do you mean not loading?
字面意思
Just what I said.
服务器没有反应
The server's not responding.
一定有人堵塞了传输系统
The hacker must be jamming the transmission.
他们究竟怎么做到的
How the hell can they do that?
要是我知道的话  我就能解决了
Well, if I knew, I'd be able to get around it.
再查查备用的摄像机
Continue checking ancillary security cams,
自动取款机  停车场
Atms, parking garages--
一定会有线索的
There has to be something.
继续调查这个区域
Well, keep canvassing the area.
可能有人会发现那辆车
Someone else may have seen the vehicle.
好的  及时告知我
That... fine. let me know.
市区的摄像机是指不上了
No luck on municipal cameras.
看起来他们已经控制了整个系统
Looks like they have someone running interference for them.
该死
Damn it.
鲍尔一定和阿尔梅达的人
Bauer must have worked out this escape
逃之夭夭了
With almeida's people.
很抱歉  拉里
I'm so sorry, larry.
那个混蛋耍了我
That son of a bitch played me.
他骗我说局里已经妥协
Had me believing the bureau was compromised
有人在内部搞鬼
Someone on the inside working against us.
现在我明白  自始至终都是他
I realize now it was him all along.
别把错误都归咎给自己
Don't put this on yourself.
我们都有责任
He played us both.
不  我应该能看出来的
No, I should have seen it.
没事了  送到楼下去
This is fine, take it downstairs.
鲍尔面临指控  将是数年的牢狱
Bauer's facing a federal indictment--years in prison.
阿尔梅达一定给他找好了出路
Almeida must have offered him a way out.
莫斯特工
Agent moss...
白宫的电话 在一号线
The white house is on line one.
好的  我去会议室接
Yeah I'll take it in the conference room.
谢谢  艾丽卡
Thanks, Erica.
我要挽回这个错误
I'm going to make this right, larry.
不管付出什么代价
Whatever it takes,
我一定要找到鲍尔和阿尔梅达
I will find Bauer and Almeida.
找到CIP装置
Well, throw in a cip device,
或许我们就能摆脱困境
And maybe we'll be off the hook.
詹尼斯  射手的情况怎么样了
Janis, what's the status of that shooter?
他还没有恢复知觉
He hasn't regained consciousness yet.
但是照片对比出来了
But a print match is just coming up now.
他叫艾伦·坦纳
His name is alan tanner.
前特工人员
He was former special forces,
沙暴行动后退役
Discharged after desert storm.
-退役  为什么   -健康原因
-Discharged why? -medical reasons.
他声称自己患了海湾综合症
He made claims to having gulf war syndrome.
并试图状告政府
Tried to sue the government,
后来不了了之
Case was dismissed.
他醒过来马上通知我
I want to be informed the minute he's awake.
好
Mm-hmm.
长官  马上为您接通
I'm connecting you now.
莫斯探员  我是伊桑·卡宁
Agent moss, this is ethan kanin.
总统也跟我在一起
I'm here with the president.
你跟你的手下
What are you and your folks doing
是怎么处理事态的
About the situation?
我让所有的探员都谨慎堤防
We put out an all-agency alert.
每个人都知道抓住阿尔梅达
Everyone understands apprehending almeida
是重中之重
Is our top priority.
他怎么逃掉的
How did he escape?
一个前ctu探员帮他的
He had the help of a former ctu agent
我们错信了那个人
That we mistakenly trusted.
他叫杰克·鲍尔
A man by the name of jack bauer.
鲍尔
Bauer?!
他不是在
I thought he was in the middle
参议院的听证会上么
Of a senate investigative hearing.
是的  长官  对的
Yes, sir, that is correct.
我们几小时前下达了一个传票
We issued a subpoena a few hours ago, excusing him
让他从听证会脱身  以便帮助我们
From the hearings in order to enlist his help
抓住阿尔梅达
In apprehending almeida.
你的意思是说这俩人现在联合了
Now you're saying that these two men are allied?
看起来是这样的
It would appear so.
天啊  你跟你的人
My god... you and your people
真的把事情搞砸了  莫斯探员
Have royally screwed up, agent moss!
没有阿尔梅达  我们就没办法找到杜巴库
Without almeida, we have no way of finding dubaku
也没机会重获cip装置
And no chance of recovering the cip device.
伊桑  咱们停留在重点上
Ethan, let's stay on point.
莫斯探员  你还有什么其它别的线索没
Agent moss, are you working any other leads?
是的  总统阁下
Yes, madame president.
阿尔梅达的一个同伙  今早受伤了
A confederate of almeida's who was wounded earlier today.
他的手术刚刚完
He's just out of surgery.
我们在等他恢复知觉
We're waiting for him to regain consciousness.
能从医院方面知道
Do we have a time frame from the hospital
他什么时候能恢复知觉么
On when that might happen?
没有的  女士
No, ma'am. not really.
我要说清楚的是  莫斯探员
Let me be clear,  agent moss
抓到阿尔梅达和鲍尔
Recapturing almeida and bauer
不仅仅是你当前最重要的任务
Isn't just your top priority,
它是你唯一的任务
It's your only priority.
明白  女士
Yes, ma'am.
和我们保持联系  探员
Keep us posted, agent.
我们要做好他们不能
Bottom line: The bureau is not going to be the answer
-解决问题的准备  -这是完全有可能的
- To our prayers here. - I'm afraid not.
我们还有多少时间
How much time does that leave us?
不到两小时了
Less than two hours.
杜巴库的要求是我方部队
Dubaku's demand is that our forces retreat
要在24小时之内后撤到子午线23度以外
Behind the 23rd meridian within 24 hours.
现在  为了保证行动的时效性
Now, in order to meet that timetable,
航母编队
The fleet and carrier air wing
最迟必须在1点钟前开始撤离
Must start withdrawing by 1:00, at the latest.
这意味着我们在非洲的行动难以维续了
Which would effectively end our mission in africa
同时也使得另外的10万桑加拉国的人民处于
And condemn another 100,000 sangalans
危险境地之中
To a certain and brutal death.
但如果您执意要继续军事行动
On the other hand, if you authorize the invasion,
杜巴库会毫不犹豫地使用手中的CIP装置
Dubaku will undoubtedly engage the cip device.
联邦航空局何时才能把飞机都全部降落下来
How far has the faa gotten with grounding aircraft?
仍然有1000多架飞机
Still over a thousand planes in the air
在我国上空等待降落
Across the country waiting for clearance to land.
杜巴库可以随时让它们中的
Dubaku could bring down
任何一架坠毁
Any one of them at any moment.
或者
Or...
甚至用那个装置去造成更恐怖的袭击
Use the device for something far worse.
作为一个总统  我的信条
I ran for office on the principle
之一就是绝不向恐怖分子妥协
Of non-negotiation with terrorists.
我怎么可能第一次遇到困难
How can I abandon that now,
就放弃这个信念
The very first time I'm tested?
并且如果我这样做
And, if I do so, won't I be telling dubaku,
不就等于告诉杜巴库和全世界
And the rest of the world,
要挟美国政府行得通吗
That blackmailing america works?
总统阁下
Madame president,
这是以后的问题
Those are questions for the future.
我们现在必须做决定
We have a decision to make now.
这是哪里
What do you call this place?
我们把这里当做是反恐组
We like to think of it as ctu.
至少是一些反恐组剩下的东西
What's left of it, anyway.
杰克
Jack...
克罗依
Chloe.
真高兴能再见到你
It's good to see you.
我也是
It's good to see you, too.
我很高兴你能站到我们这边
I'm glad you're with us.
我现在不属于任何一边
I'm not with anyone until someone starts
除非你们能够给我一个满意的答复
Answering some questions.
不如从你开始吧
Might as well start with you.
你怎么又活过来了
Why the hell are you not dead?
我当时确实死了
I was dead, jack.
死了十分钟
For almost ten minutes.
这是后来别人告诉我的
Or so I was told.
谁
By who?
这个人
By him.
他叫大卫·爱默生
His name's david emerson.
我不知道他在反恐组买通了谁
I don't know who he paid off at ctu,
但却是他的手下给我
But it was his people who injected my body
注射了一种低温药物
With a hypothermic compound,
把我救了过来
And was able to revive me.
他是谁  想干什么
Who is he and what does he want?
他似乎是一个人单干
Independent contractor.
吸纳退伍军人和情报人员
Enlists ex-military and intelligence operatives,
替客户卖命
Jobs them out to clients.
显然  我符合条件
Apparently, I fit the profile.
什么条件
What profile?
做过特工
Former employees
对政府充满怨恨
With grievances against the federal government.
自从我离开反恐组
Emerson had been keeping
爱默生一直在关注我
Tabs on me ever since I left ctu.
米歇尔被杀后
After michelle was killed...
他觉得招收我的机会到了
He figured I'd make a good recruit.
特别是其它人都认为我死了
And everyone else thinking you're dead,
这就再好不过
So much the better.
-没错  -从那时起你就
-  Yeah. - And since then, you've been
一直在为揭发他而当卧底
Working undercover to expose his operation?
不是  杰克
No, jack.
什么
What?
我当时确实在为他卖命
I was really working for him.
我恨
I was angry.
我恨联邦政府夺走了我的一切
I hated the federal government for what it took from me.
这三年来我替爱默生领导一支队伍
I ran emerson's crew for more than three years.
我干了很多令人不齿的事情
And I did some pretty bad things.
那你是怎么转变过来的
What made you turn against him?
因为CIP装置
The cip device.
爱默生让我的队伍
Emerson had my crew
去偷需要的部件以侵入防火墙  我知道这样做的结果
Stealing components to breach the firewall. I knew what that meant
无辜的美国人可能会因此丧命
Innocent americans would die.
-我不是为他来做这种事  -托尼  你太混了
-  And I didn't signed up for that. damn it, tony!
你为什么不让当局来处理
Why didn't you call the authorities?
-他做不到  杰克  -为什么
- He couldn't, jack. - Why not?
他发现爱默生的客户正是杜巴库
He found out emerson's client was dubaku.
你认为政府里有人已被他收买了
That's who you believe has agents inside the government.
朱玛独裁政府控制了桑加拉丰富的钻石资源
The juma regime controls sangala's vast diamond wealth.
他正在大肆贿赂政府人员
Dubaku hasn't been shy about throwing it around.
政府的腐败程度有多深
How widespread is the corruption?
随处可见
Pervasive.
这就是托尼找我的原因
That's why tony came to me.
因为他不知道这件事的覆盖面有多广
He didn't know how far or high up this thing went.
杰克  杜巴库是整件事的关键
Dubaku is the key to this thing, jack.
如果我们想挫败他们的阴谋
If we're going to uncover the conspiracy,
就必须在他离开美国前抓住他
We have to get to him before he leaves the u.s.
所以我必须尽快回去做卧底
That's why I have to get back under as soon as possible.
我和我手下马上就要
There's a new job in the pipeline
接手一项新任务  我还不清楚细节
For me and my crew-- I don't have all the details,
但我肯定
But I do know that it'll get me in the same room
能和杜巴库会面
With dubkau himself.
现在的问题是我们如何
The challenge is going to be
让托尼回到爱默生的团队中去
Reinstalling tony with emerson.
我们必须先假定
We have to assume
爱默生已经知道托尼被捕  要让他相信
Emerson knew tony was in fbi custody and somehow
-托尼是逃出来  -爱默生会认为
- Managed to escape. - Emerson's going to think
托尼和美国政府达成了一项交易
Tony made a deal with the u.s. attorney.
没错
That's right.
我可以帮你们解决这个问题
I can help you with this.
是的  你可以
Yes, you can.
除了你们三个
Outside of the three of you,
还有谁被牵扯了进来
Who else is involved in this operation?
没别人
It's just us.
就我们几个
This is it.
你们至少要让我
Please, at least tell me
掌握一些这个阴谋存在的证据
That you've got some proof that this conspiracy exists.
我们有证据
Yes, we do.
但不过是些皮毛
But only at the lowest level.
当前只得到一些表面的东西
At this point, we've just begun to scratch the surface.
好吧
Okay.
我和你们合作
I'll work with you.
但只因当前你们是
But only because, right now,
我唯一能够信任的人
You are the only people that I trust.
但如果你们让我稍有质疑
You give me one reason to question that,
我发誓我会告发你们
And I swear I will turn you in.
明白吗
You understand?
好吧
All right.
克罗依  准备好和爱默生的通话线路
Chloe, set up the call with emerson.
我找到两个雇佣兵
I found two freelancers who might work.
前游骑兵团成员
Ex-rangers.
-可靠吗  -当然
- You trust them? - yeah.
我和他们合作过  铁哥们
I've worked with them before. they're close.
里塔维克也认识他们
Litvak knows them, too.
-那好  -他们在加入之前
- Okay. they may want to know
想知道任务内容
More about the job before they sign on.
他们只需知道能拿到多少钱就够了
Only thing they need to know is what it pays.
好吧
All right.
喂
Yeah?
是我
It's me.
托尼
Tony.
你在哪里
Where are you?
我在一个停车场  正在设法弄辆车
I'm at a parking garage, getting a car.
我从联调局逃了出来
I got away from the fbi.
嗯  我听说了
Yeah, I heard.
还听说是杰克·鲍尔把你弄了出来
I also heard it was jack bauer who broke you out.
没错
That's right.
这事没道理  托尼
That doesn't make any sense, tony.
鲍尔替他们工作  他帮他们抓到了你
Bauer's working for them. he helped capture you.
那时他别无选择
It's only because he didn't have a choice.
他现在站在我们这边
He's on board now.
站在我们这边是什么意思
What do you mean "on board"?
今天发生在参议院听证会的事情你听说了吧
You heard about the senate hearings this morning?
他们要给他判刑
They're going to file criminal charges against him.
我告诉鲍尔  如果他帮我们完成这项任务
I told bauer that if he helped us out with the mission,
你可以帮他离开这个国家
You could get him out of the country.
大卫  如果不是杰克的话
Look, david, if it weren't for jack,
我还会被他们关着
I'd still be in custody.
我这么跟你说  我觉得我们可以利用他
We can use him, I'm telling you.
现在情况有变  托尼
I don't know, tony.
摩根已经雇了新人
Morgan's hiring new men now.
摩根是个小角色
Morgan's a thug.
没法让他指挥这么重要的行动
He can't run point on something this important.
还是按计划由我来执行吧
Let me do it like we planned.
鲍尔可以替代坦纳  这样就没问题了
Bauer can take tanner's place and we're good to go.
好吧  把鲍尔带过来
All right, bring bauer.
我们在Chesterfield 2211号
We're at 2211 chesterfield.
诺兰路边上
Right off nolan.
明白
Got it.
他信了吗
He buy it?
等会就知道了
We'll see.
泰勒先生  听说你在找我
Mr. taylor, I understand you were looking for me.
没错  盖吉探员  我想出去一下
Yes, agent gedge, I have to go out
需要一辆车
And I'm going to need some transportation.
没问题  我们要去哪里
Certainly. Where will we be going?
路上再说
I'll direct you on the way.
我得在行程单上写明目的地  先生
I need a destination for the manifest, sir.
和往常一样  不用行程单
As before, I'd like you to keep this off the manifest.
而且这次不要司机  就我们两个
And no driver this time, just you and me.
泰勒先生  我们不是说好有话直说吗
I thought we were through with all the subterfuge, mr. taylor.
照我吩咐的去做
Please just do as I ask.
对不起  先生  除非您给我个理由
I'm sorry, sir, not without an explanation.
我们去见萨曼莎·罗斯
It's samantha roth.
她说她要告诉我关于我儿子死亡的新消息
She says she has new information
是关于我儿子的死因的
Regarding my son's death.
泰勒先生
Mr. taylor...
我也以为这事过去了  相信我
I thought I was done with this, too, believe me.
不是我起的头
I didn't initiate this.
她打电话给我的
She called me.
布莱恩
Brian...
我知道报告我先前的行踪是你的职责所在
I know you felt obligated to report my prior activities--
这也是正确的  但是我还是希望
And rightly so-- but I would still like to think
在需要你对我的忠诚的时候  你能做到
That I can count on your loyalty when I ask for it.
我会丢了饭碗的  先生
I could lose my job, sir.
这是最后一次了  我保证
This will be the last time. I promise.
亨利
Henry?
求你了
Please.
安排好车  我会马上打电话给你
I'll call you as soon as I secure a vehicle.
谢谢
Thank you.
谁啊
Who was that?
工作人员  没什么
Staff, nothing.
能帮我戴上么
Here, can you help me with this?
当然
Sure.
是爸爸给我的礼物
It was a gift from my father.
你记得吗
You remember? mm-hmm.
就是我赢回他参议院席位的那天
On the day I won back his seat in the senate.
总理马托波想要见我
Prime minister matobo has asked to see me.
他想要知道
He's going to want to know
为什么我还没下令进兵
Why I haven't authorized the invasion yet.
那你怎么跟他说
What are you going to tell him?
我也不知道
I don't know.
美国人民选你
The american people elected you
是因为他们相信你的判断力  艾莉森
Because they trust your judgment, allison,
而且他们相信你
And they're going to trust you
会在这件事上做出正确决定的
To make the right call on this, too.
可我不知道什么才是正确的决定
I don't know what the right call is.
正确的决定
The right call...
就是你做的任何一个决定
Is whatever you decide it is.
有多少外勤小队
How many units in the field?
十七个  能上的都上了
17-- all available agents are deployed.
扩大搜索网  必须假想鲍尔和阿尔梅达
Widen the grid-- we have to assume
已经逃出了我们的搜索范围
Bauer and almeida have gotten outside of our perimeter by now.
这就办
On it.
西恩·希林格
Sean hillinger.
西恩  是我
Sean, its me.
克里斯蒂娜
Christina.
-你在哪啊  -我在飞机上呢
-Where are you? -I'm calling from the plane.
你的飞机还没降落吗
You haven't landed yet?
没呢  飞行员说我们在等待航线
No, th-the pilot says we're in a holding pattern...
但是我们就是在这一圈一圈地转
But we just keep circling and circling,
而且我能从窗户里看到其它的飞机
And I can see other planes out the window, too--
至少有八九架呢
Eight or nine, at least.
克里斯蒂娜  宝贝  放松些
Christina, sweetheart, relax.
但是坐我旁边的女人说
But the woman sitting next to me says
她听说有两架飞机差点相撞
She heard something about a near miss
还听说航管系统也有问题
And a problem with the air traffic control system.
西恩  你知道这些情况吗
Sean, do you know anything about this?
是的  都是事实
Yeah, it's true.
航管局已经限飞了一些飞机
The FAA has grounded some planes, but it's only
但只是预防措施罢了
A precaution.
真的吗
Really?
对  其实是个无关的事故
Yeah, it was an isolated incident.
你会没事的
You're going to be fine.
好吧
Okay.
我只是  有些担心
I just... I got worried there for a minute.
你了解我的
You know how I am.
我了解你
I do.
听我说  飞机一落地你就给我打电话
Now, listen, I want you to call me as soon as you land.
我会的
I will.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你老婆啊
Was that your wife?
詹尼斯告诉我  你老婆的飞机还没落地
Janis told me her plane's still in the air.
你没事吧
You okay?
一个疯子在那有能力随意
Okay, there's a maniac out there with the capability
损毁飞机  所以  不  艾瑞卡
Of bringing down planes at will, so, no, erika,
我有事  她的飞机排到第18个降落
I'm not okay. her flight is number 18
至少还要2个小时
In the queue, so it'll be another two hours, at least,
她才能够安全
Before hers gets clearance.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我能做点什么吗
Is there anything I can do?
没有
No.
不能  我们无能为力  这就是问题所在
No, there's nothing anybody can do; that's the problem.
对  她就在这  我告诉她
Yeah, she's right here. I'll let her know.
谢谢  再见
Thank you, bye-bye.
蕾妮
Renee.
我刚跟医院通过电话
I just got off the phone with the hospital.
坦纳恢复知觉了
Tanner's regained consciousness.
他能说话吗
Is he well enough to talk?
已经好到可以叫医生替他打电话了
He's well enough to ask the doctor to make a phone call for him.
他打给谁了
Who did he call?
盖奇·惠特尼·佩斯  我想是律师事务所吧
Gage whitney pace, which is a law firm, I think.
华盛顿第二大的
The second largest in dc.
带上你的本本跟我走  詹尼斯
Go grab your laptop, janis. you're coming with me.
我吗
I am?
-为什么  -因为我们必须赶在坦纳的律师
-Why?-because we have to get to tanner
到之前赶到医院
before his lawyers do
如果我能从他那得到阿尔梅达所在位置
And because if I can get almeida's location out of him,
我要你把消息马上传达到外勤小组手里
I want you on-site to vet the intelligence to our field teams.
-快去  -好吧
-Go. -okay.
跟我讲讲爱默生
Tell me about emerson.
他是英国人  前英国空军特种兵
He's british, former sas.
惯于城市作战  擅长狙击和近距离格斗
Urban warfare, sniping, close-quarter combat.
看过他在贝鲁特和摩加迪沙的行动
Saw action in beirut and mogadishu.
那他很强咯
So he's good.
相当的强
Extremely.
但是他不是什么怪人或者理学家
But he's not some wack job or ideologue.
他这人就两条  钱和个人忠诚
He's about two things-- money and personal loyalty.
看起来你仍然很崇拜他
Sounds like you still admire him.
听着  杰克
Listen, jack,
当我孤苦伶仃之时
He treated me like a brother
他对我情同兄弟
When I thought I had nobody else.
这样会有问题吗
Is this going to be a problem?
不会
No.
我知道在这件事上他做错了
I know he's on the wrong side of this.
我会公事公办的
I'll do what has to be done.
我们到了
We're here.
爱默生在哪
Where's emerson?
在里面
Inside.
进来吧
Come in.
大卫
David.
见到你很高兴
Good to see you.
把鲍尔带到楼下  我要跟托尼谈谈
Take mr. bauer downstairs. I need to talk to tony.
怎么了
What's going on?
带鲍尔来是不是太冒险了
Bringing in bauer is not worth the risk.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
请坐
Have a seat.
爱默生一会就来见你
Emerson will be right with you.
如果不是他  我还被FBI关着呢
I'd still be in fbi custody if it wasn't for him.
托尼  你已经暴露了
Tony, you already made your case.
我们可以利用他
We can use him.
这个我考虑过  但我另有妙计
I considered it... but I'm going a different way.
我欠他的  大卫
I owe him, david.
你明白吗
You understand that?
我明白  我很赞赏你对朋友的忠诚
Yeah, and I appreciate your sense of loyalty.
始终如一  但你得公事公办  托尼
I always have, but this is business, tony.
你不能找个不明身份的杰克·鲍尔
You can't have a... an unknown factor like jack bauer
来搅局
Coming in and messing things up.
那怎么办  你要杀了他
So, what, you're going to kill him?
不  你去杀
No, you are.
他们要杀了他
They're going to kill him.
他会逃脱的
He'll get out of it.
-如果不能呢  -那杰克的死
-What if he can't? -then jack's death
会巩固托尼的身份
Solidifies tony's position in the crew.
托尼曾经被FBI拘留过
Tony was in fbi custody.
如果他自己回到那了
If he'd gone back in there by himself,
怀疑会落到他一个人头上
The suspicion would have rested on him alone.
现在分散到杰克身上了
So by deflecting it onto jack...
我们就可以保持托尼的卧底身份
We keep tony's cover viable.
你早预料到这个结局了
You knew this might happen the whole time.
是
Yes.
杰克也预料到了
So did jack.
放下你的武器
Put your weapon down!
放下武器  不然我就杀了他
Put your weapon down or I will kill him!
我是来做事的  不是来被你出卖的
I came here to do a job, not be double-crossed by you.
你们已经人手不足了
You're already shorthanded.
你需要精兵强将  不是这俩窝囊废
You need good men, not like these two traffic cops.
看看我是怎么收拾他们的
Look what I've done to them.
我来这是因为我无路可走了
I am here because I've got nowhere else to go.
托尼说如果我帮你
Tony said if I helped you,
你可以帮我逃出这个国家
You could get me out of the country.
你要是不信我的话  就开枪吧
Look, if you don't believe me, pull the trigger.
搞什么  你疯了吗
What, are you crazy?!
杀了他
Kill him!
不
No.
杀了他  否则我就不干了
Kill him or I'm out of here.
好吧
Fine.
枪留着
Keep it.
好吧  让112号航班
Right, I need flight 112 reassigned
立即降落
For immediate landing.
你请求112号航班在洛杉矶外
So you're requesting a priority landing for flight 112
-优先降落吗  -这不是请求
Out of las vegas? this is not a request.
这是给你转达白宫发出的紧急协议
I'm forwarding an urgent protocol from the white house.
您的名字是
And your name was...
拉里·莫斯  我是负责此事的探员
Larry Moss, special agent in charge.
此事关系到国家的安危
This is a matter of national security.
莫斯探员
Agent moss,
请告诉我你的5级通行号码
May I have your level five access number?
6223-510
6223-510.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
112号航班将被排在首位
Flight 112 is moved to the head of the queue
稍后即将着陆
And should be on the ground shortly.
谢谢
Thank you.
泰勒总统
President taylor,
我是埃克·杜巴库上校
This is colonel ike dubaku.
如你所料
As you have no doubt confirmed,
肯尼迪机场的事故并非意外
The near-collision at jfk international was no accident.
我们有CIP装置
We have the cip device.
我们有能力杀掉
We have the capability to kill
数以万计的美国公民
Tens of thousands of americans
而且我们已经准备这么做了
And we are prepared to do so.
我希望你亲耳听听  总理阁下
I wanted you to hear it for yourself, prime minister,
这样一来你就能明白我的困境了
So that you would understand my dilemma.
明白
I see.
你是想召回特遣部队
You are recalling the invasion force.
我还没打定主意
Well, that determination has yet to be made.
杜巴库所掌握的这种设备
And this device over which dubaku has control,
对你的人民造成了
It poses a significant risk
-极大的威胁  -是的
- To your people? - yes.
该装置能引起大量
It's a technology that has the potential
平民伤亡
For mass civilian casualties.
它还对我国的基础设施有严重威胁
And it puts the infrastructure of my country in grave jeopardy.
桑加拉那边怎么办
What of sangala?
相信我  没人比我更清楚局势
Believe me, no one is more aware of what's at stake than i.
这么说来你已得知卡桑加省的情况
So you've been informed of the situation in kasanga province?
朱玛的军队正向难民营推进
Juma's troops are advancing on a refugee camp.
2000多人的生命受到威胁
Over 2,000 lives are threatened.
其中大多是妇女和儿童
Mostly women and children.
同时还有我国那些
There is also the matter of those soldiers who have,
受到美国支持所鼓舞的士兵
On the promise of american support,
放弃了政府  转而加入
Deserted the regime and joined
我的自由军之列的士兵
My freedom fighters on the ground.
至少...
At least...
请我们提供所需要的武器装备
Provide us the weapons we need in order
来保卫自己
To defend ourselves.
你得有耐心  马托波先生
You've been patient with us before, mr. matobo.
我唯一的要求就是希望你再多点耐心
I can only ask that you be patient again.
请原谅  我还有事
Now, please, if you'll excuse me.
总统阁下  我求你了
Madame president, I implore you,
别放弃我的国家
Do not abandon my country.
马托波先生  我会尽我所能
Mr. matobo, I will do everything that I can.
全靠你了
I count on you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不觉得我想知道
You didn't think that I would want
卡桑加难民的情况吗
To know about the refugees in kasanga?
总统阁下  您没必要
Madame president, you have enough to think about
在这种小事上浪费心思
Without being burdened with details.
尤其是这种
Especially details that might push me toward
会将我卷入战争的小事
Proceeding with the invasion.
总统阁下  您只能把精力
Ma'am, you have to start
集中在备选方案上
Focusing on alternatives to the invasion.
那你给我个好点的选择
Give me a good alternative
-让我考虑下  -我并不是说这样就好
And I'll consider it. I'm not saying it's a good alternative,
这是唯一的出路
But it's the only one.
照杜巴库要求的做
Comply with dubaku's demands.
撤回特遣部队
Stand down the task force.
多谢你的提点
That's your recommendation?
放弃
Back down?
对
It is.
该死  伊桑  你也听见马托波说的了
Damn it, ethan, you heard matobo.
他的部队还全指望我们
He's has fighters on the ground counting on us.
你想让我重演猪湾事件吗
Do you want me to be responsible for another bay of pigs?
肯尼迪能在其中幸存
Kennedy survived the bay of pigs,
您也可以
And you'll survive this.
超级大国行事就是要把自己的利益
A superpower has to act first and foremost in its own
放在首位
Best interests.
-一直如此  -一直
- Always? - always.
不需要道歉
No apologies.
也包括让第三方
What about allowing a third party
对其发号施令吗
To dictate its foreign policy
这是一个超级大国应该做得吗
does a superpower do that?
是的  在没有其他选择余地时
Yes, if there's no other option.
而如今  就是如此
And right now, there's not.
FBI那边对阿尔梅达和鲍尔
What have we heard from the fbi about the search
的搜寻工作进展如何
For almeida and bauer?
没什么起色  总统阁下
Nothing, ma'am.
想办法与他们协商
Check with them anyway.
并无恶意  杰克
No hard feelings, Jack?
没关系
Forget it.
干我们这行就得处处小心
Have to be careful in our profession.
这你能理解
I'm sure you understand.
-是的  -我们都懂
- Yeah. - we all know the drill.
欢迎不同意见
Disagreements are fine,
一旦尘埃落定
But when a decision's made,
遵守之或者死亡
Fall in or you're gone.
听不少人说过
I've heard a lot of guys say that.
很高兴你是当真的
Good to know you mean it.
被传讯前
Before you were subpoenaed,
你在外游历一年多  到处都去
You traveled the world, place to place, more than a year.
这是为什么
Why?
你在找什么
What were you looking for?
这无关紧要
It doesn't really matter.
不管是什么  我都没找到
Whatever it was, I didn't find it.
你肯定知道会发生什么
You must have known what was waiting.
那你为什么回来
Why'd you come back?
来体验下走进直升机的感觉
Wanted to know what it was like to walk into a propeller.
真有意思
That's funny.
不过  说实话
But no, really.
为什么
Why?
这是我的家
This is my home.
那可解释不了  你为何
That doesn't explain why you turned yourself in
向司法部门自首
To the justice department.
托尼说你去过贝鲁特和摩加迪沙
Tony said you were in beirut and mogadishu.
还有阿富汗
And afghanistan.
两次旅行
Two tours.
第三次是以私人承包商的身份去的
Went back a third time as a private contractor.
以礼相待  专业人士
Be polite, professional,
还计划把你见到的每个人都杀掉  对吗
And have a plan to kill everyone you meet, right?
大致如此
Pretty much.
这就是问题所在  对吗
That's the question, isn't it?
不成夫妻便成仇人是吧
Where do the rules of engagement end and the crimes begin?
想知道我为什么回来吗
You want to know why I came back?
这就是原因
That's why.
我没太听明白
I'm not sure I follow.
我已经厌倦了自言自语的日子
I just got tired of talking to myself.
我深信做过的每一件事都是正确的
You see, I actually believe everything I did was right.
所以我想说出来
So I wanted to start a dialogue.
坦白说  就是澄清事实
Come clean, set the record straight.
可惜想错了
First mistake.
是啊我发现了
So I found out.
没有过如此经历
No one who hasn't been to the edge and looked over
永远不会明白
Can ever understand.
对
Yeah.
很高兴拉你入伙了  杰克
It's good to have you on board, jack.
喂
Yeah?
怎么了
What was that about?
他想套我的话
He's just trying to get a handle on me.
多加小心  杰克
Watch yourself around him, Jack.
别低估了他
And do not underestimate him.
不会的
I won't.
好了  都听着
All right, listen up.
我刚接到电话
I just got the call.
-现在出发  -去干什么
- We're a go. - a go for what?
我们都不知道任务是什么
We don't even know what the hell the job is.
去取个包裹  送到客户手中
Picking up a package, delivering it to our client.
这是地点
Here's the location.
福克斯浩大街167号
A residence at 167 foxhall road.
那是国务院的地方
It belongs to the state department.
记住地形  我们不知道
Memorize the layout. we don't know
还不知具体取货地点
The exact spot of the pickup yet,
可能会在主套间内
But probably the master suite.
包裹是个人
The package is a person.
没错
Yeah, it is.
桑加拉的前总理  马托波
Former prime minister Matobo of Sangala.
任务就是抓住他
The assignment is to grab him
并送去杜巴库上校处
And deliver him to Colonel Dubaku.
上校想问他一些问题
The colonel wants to ask him some questions,
你能想象得到
And as you can imagine,
上校很有说服力
The colonel can be quite persuasive.
马托波已加强保安
Now, Matobo has tight security,
带上武器  做好交火的准备
So finish arming up, be prepared to engage.
2分钟后行动
We roll in two minutes.
他们要绑架马托波
They're going to kidnap Matobo.
必须发出警告才能阻止此事
We have to alert somebody and stop this.
不  我们按兵不动
No, we do nothing.
可你听到了  他们很可能会
But you heard them-- they're going
严刑拷打他  还可能会杀了他
To torture him and probably kill him.
很不幸  我们没办法
Unfortunately, yes.
马托波单枪匹马领军对抗
Matobo single-handedly led the fight
国内的大屠杀
Against genocide in his country.
-他不该受死  -我明白  克罗伊
- He doesn't deserve this. - I understand that, chloe.
如果我们阻挠劫持
But if we don't go along with the grab,
杰克和托尼就无法找到杜巴库上校
Jack and Tony will not find colonel Dubaku,
我们就无法深入了解此阴谋
And we will not get to the bottom of this conspiracy.
明白吗
Agreed?
是的
Agreed.
-别等我  -先生
- I don't want you to wait for me. - Sir?
把车开走
Just drive away.
需要你时  我会叫你的
I'll call when I need you.
你知道我不能擅离职守  泰勒先生
You know I can't do that, Mr. Taylor.
我们此行是秘密行动  布莱恩
We're already off the manifest, Brian.
我若不单刀赴会  她不会告诉我
She won't talk to me unless I'm alone.
好吧  我在桥上待命
All right, I'll take up a position on the bridge.
她不会发现我
She'll never know I'm there.
好的
All right.
-泰勒先生  -萨姆
- Mr. Taylor. - Sam.
我不能久留
I can't stay long.
你电话里所说
What you told me on the phone,
是真的吗
Is it true?
是的  他们杀了罗杰并伪装成自杀
Yes, they killed Roger and made it look like a suicide.
谁  是谁干的
Who? who did this?
那些人还伪造了
The same people who provided
证券交易委员会的文档
False documents to the sec to show
污蔑他内幕交易
He'd been trading on inside information.
-他们是谁  -我不知道
- Who are they? - I don't know who they are.
他们说如果我透露半个字  就杀了我
They just said that they would kill me if I said anything.
放松  萨姆  放松
Easy, easy, Sam. easy.
我爱他
I loved him.
我知道  萨姆
I know you did, Sam.
现在  我需要知道真相
But right now, I really need to know what happened.
罗杰被安排审计部门内部的经纪人
Roger was tasked with auditing the brokers in his department.
一切由此开始
That's how it started.
-什么时候的事  -一月
- When was this? - January.
一月初
Uh, early January.
合规律师要求他查出
The compliance officer at his firm asked him to flag
公司内所有安全部门的秘密所有权
Any undisclosed ownership in securities positions.
我不明白
I don't understand.
就是回扣
Basically, kickbacks.
但他发现的不止这些
But what he found was something else.
有两位部门经理受理了一位新客户
Two of his portfolio managers had taken on a new client.
在巴哈马分部
The Bahamas branch
洛桑国际银行
Bank Lausanne International.
有什么不对吗
What was wrong with that?
洛桑银行的记录显示
Bank Lausanne's records revealed that
该帐户与多家桑加拉的公司
It was actively trading with firms
存在合作贸易
Doing business in sangala.
-桑加拉  -罗杰当时也不以为然
- Sangala?! - It jumped out at Roger, too,
表面没有问题  但深入调查后
For obvious reasons, and digging deeper,
他发现一些可疑帐户
He uncovered other blind accounts
正在复制银行的交易
That were copying the bank's trades.
哪些帐户
Which accounts?
这些帐户追查至
Accounts that were traced to a senior member
你妻子的一位高级内阁
Of your wife's administration.
谁
Who?
我不知道
I don't know.
不论是谁  此人利用军事行动
But whoever it was had a vested interest in the proposed
为自己牟利
Military action.
是某个不信任她的人
Somebody who was betting against her,
不相信她有能力取得政治胜利
Who didn't think she'd be able to pull it off politically?
他以大量股份为赌注
Betting heavily in 10,000-share blocks.
罗杰还差一两天
Roger was a day or two away
就打算将证据交给总统
From presenting her with the evidence.
都在这里
It's all here.
账号
Account numbers,
交易记录  他所知的一切
Trading records, everything that he knew.
抱歉  我只能帮到这里
I'm sorry that I can't help you out more.
-萨曼莎  -我知道的都告诉你了
- Samantha... - I've given you all I can.
随你做什么  别牵连我
Do what you have to do, but leave me out of it.
求你了
Please?
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
坦纳在里面
Is tanner in there?
是的  他情况尚不稳定
Yes. his condition is still listed as critical.
他的律师来了吗
Are his lawyers here yet?
还没  但随时会到
No. but they will be any minute.
去大厅盯着他们
Okay, get down to the lobby and keep an eye out for them.
他们一进医院马上通知我
Call me as soon as they enter the hospital.
明白
Got it.
进来
Come on.
坦纳先生
Hello, Mr. Tanner.
我是沃克探员
I'm agent Walker.
这位是格尔探员  我们是联邦探员
This is agent Gold. we're with the FBI.
你应该记得我
I think you remember me.
我知道你很疼  我长话短说
I know you're in pain, so I'll make this brief.
告诉我托尼·阿尔梅达在哪
Tell me where Tony Almeida is.
阿尔梅达还有其他行动据点吗
Does Almeida have another base of operations?
CIP装置是否在那里
Is that where the CIP device is?
我的律师
My lawyers...
帮不了你  坦纳先生
Cannot help you, Mr. Tanner.
你的余生将在监狱中度过
You're going to spend the rest of your life in prison
如果你不合作的话
If you don't cooperate.
若你合作  我向你保证
But if you do, I give you my word,
我将为你提供担保
I will personally vouch for you.
帮我找到装置能令你
Helping me find the device can go a long way
减轻多年的刑罚
Towards reducing your sentence.
抱歉  有什么可笑的吗
I'm sorry. Is something funny?
他们不会允许的
They'd never let that happen.
他们是谁  杜巴库上校
Who is they? Colonel Dubaku?
托尼·阿尔梅达听他的指挥行动吗
Is that who tony almeida takes his orders from?
你是否也为他工作
Do you work for him too?
走开
Go away.
睁开眼睛  坦纳先生
Open your eyes, Mr. Tanner.
我叫你睁开眼睛
I said open your eyes.
看着我  杜巴库是否来到了美国
Look at me! Is Dubaku here in this country?
他是否拿到了装置
Does he have the device?
蕾妮  蕾妮  蕾妮
Renee... Renee, Renee...
别这样  蕾妮
Please. Renee...
我不知道你在做什么
I don't know what you're doing.
你到底在做什么
What are you doing?
沃克
Walker.
坦纳的律师到了
Tanner's lawyers just arrived.
好的  谢谢
All right, thanks.
他的法律后援团来了
His legal team is here.
我需要你拖住他们
I need you to stall them.
我  我该怎么做
Me? how am I supposed to do that?
我不管  你随意发挥
I don't care. make something up.
必须尽量拖住他们  越久越好
Just keep them out of this room as long as you can.
我觉得此举不妥
I'm not comfortable with this.
什么不妥
Comfortable with what?
我们违反了一大堆联邦条例
We are breaking about 50 federal guidelines
-就为了来这里  -听我说  詹尼斯
- Just by being here. - Listen to me, Janis.
此人是我们唯一的线索
This man is our only lead.
他要求法律顾问到场
That man asked for legal counsel.
我听到了
I heard him.
数千人命悬于此
Thousands of lives are at stake here.
如果此时不歪曲一些规定
We either bend the rules a little bit right now
我们将永远失去良机
Or we lose this chance forever.
抱歉  抱歉  我  我不能
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I just... I can't.
听着  托尼·阿尔梅达和杰克·鲍尔
Look, Tony Almeida and Jack Bauer
在我眼皮底下逃脱
Escaped custody on my watch.
我必须弥补过失
I have to make this right.
你帮不帮我
You either help me or you don't.
好吧
Okay.
先生们  打扰了
Excuse me. Gengtleman
你的时候不多了  坦纳
You're out of time, Mr. Tanner.
把你知道的事告诉我
Tell me what you know.
随你怎么处置我
You can do what you want to me.
我半句话都不会告诉你
I'm not going to tell you a damn thing.
你在为谁卖命
Who do you work for?!
你不能这样
You can't do this...
阿尔梅达在哪里
Where is Almeida?
CIP装置在哪里  快说
How do I find the CIP device? Tell me now.
我的律师
My lawyers...
你不能这样
You can't do this.
你是联邦探员
You're FBI.
你这样做违法
This is illegal.
我有我的权利
I have rights.
我建议你的下句话要慎重
I suggest you use your last breath wisely.
去死吧
Go to hell.
我向你保证我是认真对待这件事的
I assure you, I'm taking this very seriously.
那就告诉我们客户在哪里
Then tell us where our client is.
我说过出于安全原因  他换房了
As I said, he was moved for security reasons.
转到了别间吗
Into the annex?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
那他怎么没在那里
Then why isn't he there?
不如我给办公室打个电话
Listen, if I can just get on the phone, I'll call my office.
查个明白
We'll get to the bottom of this...
用不着你帮忙了  古德探员
We've had enough of your help, Agent Gold.
我也很迷糊
I... I'm genuinely confused too.
请问
Excuse me.
我们的客户阿兰·坦纳先生在哪里
We're trying to find our client, Mr. Alan Tanner.
稍等
Just a minute.
有个呼吸机出现故障
I've got a ventilator malfunction.
可恶  他快不行了
Damn it! He's coding!
去找人  去推急救车  快
Get a team and a crash cart over here, STAT!
421房  坦纳
Room 421, Tanner.
好像是堵住了
It's blocked or something.
我们得进去
We have to get in there!
我在努力
I'm trying to!
喂  开门
Hello?! Open this door!
这是紧急情况
This is an emergency!
门打不开  卡住了
I can't get the door open. It's jammed!
有人和他在里面吗
Is somebody in there with him?
把他交给你了  律师
He's all yours, Counselor.
等下  我们找你有事
Wait a minute. We need to talk to you!
别问  詹妮斯  不是什么好事
You don't want to know, Janis. Don't ask.
让阿尔维斯送你回总部
Have Agent Alves drive you back to the office.
希林格
Hillinger.
让我和拉里说话
Let me speak to Larry.
长官  沃克在线上
Sir, I've got Walker on the line.
有何消息
Did you get anything?
可能得到一条阿尔梅达的线索
I may have a lead on Almeida.
他们策划绑架前总理桑加拉
Apparently, there's a plot in place against the former prime minister Sangala.
马托波吗
Matobo?
坦纳说阿尔梅达的手下密谋绑架他
Tanner says Almeida's crew has a plan to abduct him.
何时
When?
差不多就是现在
Pretty much now.
拉里  如果阿尔梅达仍参与此事
Listen, Larry, if Almeida's still a part of this,
我们可以提前赶到那里守株待兔
and we can get there before him, we can set a trap.
好
All right.
我会警告总理的安保人员
I'll alert the prime minister's security detail
并派一支特警队过去
and scramble a Tac Team.
马托波住在国务院住宅区
Matobo's housed in a State Department residence:
地址是167 Foxhall Road
167 Foxhall Road
蕾妮  不要单独行动  等我增援
Renee, do not go in alone. Wait for backup.
好
Right.
喂
Yes.
是依托奥上校吗
Is this Major Etolo?
对
It is.
我是联调局的特工拉里·莫斯
This is Special Agent Larry Moss, FBI.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
口令是AAD
Code: alpha alpha delta.
拘禁总理
Lock the prime minister down.
重复一遍  拘禁总理
I repeat, lock him down.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
准备完毕  上
We're clear. Go.
马托波在哪里
Where's Matobo?!
他在哪里
Where is he?!
发现他了
I got him!
放下武器  快
Drop the weapon! Now!
放下枪  跪下
Put the gun down! On your knees!
马托波在哪里
Where is Matobo?
你们现在别想抓到他
You will not be able to get to him now.
出了什么事  乌雷
What is happening, Ule?
他们是谁
Who is doing this to us?
冷静  没事
Stay calm. It's going to be all right.
电话坏了
It's dead.
是个避难所  钢筋混凝土结构
It's a safe room; Reinforced concrete.
我们怎么就没想到这点
Why the hell didn't we know about this?
给你三秒时间打开那道门
You have three seconds to open the door.
一
One...
打不开
I can't.
二
Two...
没法从外面打开
It can't be unlocked from the outside.
只能从里面打开
It can only be opened from the inside.
杰克  如果我们空手而回
Jack, if we leave here without Matobo,
我们就会失去见到杜巴库的唯一机会
we lose our only chance of getting at Dubaku.